- Before we explore YouTube, I'd like to take
قبل از شروع آموزش یوتیوب
just a brief moment to introduce myself.
معرفی مختصری از من را داشته باشیم.
I've been creating web content for many years.
من برای سالهای طولانی محتوا تولید کرده ام.
In fact, I put my first video up online back in 1996.
در حقیقت اولین ویدئو خودم را در سال 1996 آپلود کرده ام
So I've been at this for awhile with encoding video.
بنابراین مدتی است در این کار بوده ام.
I've managed websites for many years,
و وبسایت ها را برای سالهای زیادی مدیریت کرده ام
including those on photography and music
که شامل عکاسی و ویدئو نیز بوده اند
and I've always relied upon different ways
و همیشه از راههای مختلف اشتراک گذاری تصویر و صدا
of sharing audio and video content
استفاده کرده ام
to really distribute to the masses.
تا درمیان مردم پخش شوند
Now, YouTube is a big part of that strategy
در حال حاضر یوتیوب یک راه حل بزرگ برای اینکار است
and I'll share with you some of the lessons I've learned
و من درسهایی که در طول سالیان آموخته ام
through the years.
را با شما به اشتراک می گذارم
I've also authored about 40 books
من بیش از 40 کتاب درباره عکاسی، ویدئو و بیزینس
for things about photography, video, and business.
نوشته ام
So many of these have been official texts
که شامل متن های زیادی
for Adobe and Apple and a lot of content on web video.
برای ادوب و اپل و تولید محتوا بوده است
In fact, I wrote the first book on video podcasting,
در حقیقت من اولین کتابم را در مورد ویدئو پادکست کردن نوشته ام
which is a precursor to a lot of things
که در خیلی از موارد پیشرو بوده است
that have happened now and migrated over to YouTube.
مواردی که الان اتفاق افتاده و در یوتیوب رخ داده است
I'm very familiar with the concept
من بسیار با محتوای خلق محتوا I'm very familiar with the concept
of creating content for the web specifically,
و انتشار آن برای افراد
and distributing it out to folks to consume
به طور منظم
on a regular basis.
آشنا هستم
I've recorded more than 150 online classes,
من بیش از 150 کلاس آنلاین ضبط کرده ام
so making online content is something
پس خلق محتوای آنلاین چیزی است که
I'm very familiar with.
بسیار با آن آشنایی دارم
And I regularly publish two websites.
و من به طور منظم دو سایت را پابلیش کرده ام.
A personal blog and a daily blog about photography
یک وبلاگ شخصی و یک وبلاگ روزانه در ارتباط با عکاسی
that's been published with multiple authors
که با چندین نویسنده پابلیش شده است
coming up on 20 years now.
و به 20 سال سابقه رسیده است
I also serve as the program manager for the
من مدیر برنامه برای I also serve as the program manager for the
National Association of Broadcasters
کنفرانس جهانی National Association of Broadcasters
for their post-production world conference.
انجمن ملی پخش کنندگان هستم.
This is a conference that has been around
این کنفرانس در حدود دو قرن
for almost two decades and it helps people
وجود داشته
learn and master new skills about video editing,
و به مردم درباره ادیت کردن ویدئو و
production, post-production, and distributing content
ساخت و ادیت و توزیع محتوا به جهان
to the world.
آموزش می دهد.
I also keep myself busy as an owner
از طرفی نقشی به عنوان صاحب
of a video production company.
یک کمپانی تولید ویدئو ایفا می کنم
And we're frequently called upon to make content
و مداما از ما خواسته می شود تا
for YouTube and to help people with things
برای یوتیوب محتوا تولید کنیم و
like live streaming and live events.
به مردم درباره مواردی مثل پخش زنده کمک کنیم
Creating content for the web is something
تولید محتوا برای وبسایت چیزی است که
that I've had the pleasure of doing a lot of.
من از انجام آن بسیار لذت می برم
As such, I've made a lot of mistakes through the years
من اشتباهات زیادی در طول سالها مرتکب شده ام
and have had a lot of opportunities to learn best practices.
و فرصت های زیادی برای آموزش داشتم
We've been able to put this into practice
به ما فرصت این داده شد که
for many different companies and brands you might recognize.
برای برندهای زیادی که ممکن است شما بشناسید از این موارد استفاده کنیم
A partial client roster includes the fact
بخشی از فهرست مشتریان نمایانگر این است که
that we've done work for companies like
ما برای کمپانیهایی مثل
Apple, Adobe, Canon, Cisco, Drobo, Google,
Apple, Adobe, Canon, Cisco, Drobo, Google,
KelbyOne, Lynda.com, Microsoft, and Skylum Software.
KelbyOne, Lynda.com, Microsoft, Skylum Software تولید محتوا کرده ایم.
As you can see we've been around the block.
همانطوری که میبینید ما مدت طولانی ای در این زمینه کار کرده ایم
And as such I have pretty strong opinions
و نظرات قوی ای در ارتباط با اینکه
about what works and what doesn't work.
چه چیزی موثر است و چه چیزی موثر نیست داریم
To be perfectly honest there's things about YouTube
اگر بخواهم با شما صادق باشم مواردی در یوتیوب وجود دارد که
that drive me crazy.
مرا دیوانه می کند
And there are things about the terms of service
و مواردی در ارتباط با قوانین استفاده وجود دارد
that I want to make sure you are keenly aware of.
که می خواهم شما از آن آگاه باشید
In this course, while we're going to explore
در این دوره در حین جستجو در موارد تکنیکی
a lot of technical things, I'm also going to share with you
من به شما پیشنهادات عملی در هنگام استراتژی ها
practical advice when it comes to having a strategy,
و ملاحظات تجاری
as well as some business considerations
خواهم داد
you need to keep in mind if YouTube
شما باید در نظر داشته باشید که
is going to be a part of your platform.
یوتیوب بخشی از پلت فرم شما خواهد بود
Through the years we've also produced
در طول این سالها
a lot of different types of content.
ما مدل های مختلفی از محتوا را تولید کرده ایم
We've produced videos on a wide range of topics
ما ویدئوهایی در ارتباط با تکنولوژی تا مواردی در ارتباط با عکاسی
from technology and photography
و طراحی گرافیک و مد
to graphic design and fashion.
تولید کرده ایم
We've worked with a lot of clients who are producing
ما با مشتریان بسیاری که محتوا برای سلامتی و والدین
content for health and parenting.
تولید می کنند کار کرده ایم
As well as even the college admissions process,
و همینطور درمورد روال قبولی در دانشگاه
education, fundraising, fitness, and many other areas.
تحصیلات، خیریه، ورزش و موارد زیاد دیگر
Now, a lot of you know me as an on-camera trainer
حالا تعدادی زیادی از شما مرا بعنوان یک مدرس
producing courses like this one that you watch.
که آموزشهایی مثل همین چیزی که مشاهده می کنید می شناسید
But we spend far more time at my company
ولی ما زمان زیادی بر روی شرکت من که
helping other people produce content for the web.
به مردم برای تولید محتوا در وب کمک می کند صرف کرده ایم
So I'm usually actually behind a camera
بنابراین من معمولا پشت دوربین هستم
and that's going to be some of the lessons
و این شامل دروسی خواهد بود که
I share with you today.
من امروز با شما به اشتراک خواهم گذاشت
What have I learned producing content for YouTube
چیزی که من در حین تولید محتوا برای یوتیوب
as well as how to put the channels together.
در حین کنار هم گذاشتن کانالها آموخته ایم
We've had the benefit of managing some YouTube channels
ما برای چندین برند در طی سالها
for a few different brands through the years
کانالهای یوتیوب مدیریت کرده ایم
and we've learned a lot about how to make the platform
و آموخته ایم که چگونه می توان برای گرفتن نتایج خوب
give us good results.
پلت فرم ساخت